{"tossups": [{"question": "This man founded the State Research Bureau to persecute the Acholi and Langi ethnic groups. After seizing power from Milton Obote, this man renamed his palace \u201cThe Command Post\u201d and expelled 50,000 Asian from his country. This dictator led a failed invasion of a country led by Julius Nyerere and allegedly ordered the murder of (*) Dora Bloch. After this man allowed a PLO-hijacked plane to enter his country, Israeli Special Forces responded with the Raid on Entebbe. For 10 points, name this self-declared \u201cConqueror of the British Empire\u201d and notorious dictator of Uganda.", "answer": "Idi Amin Dada", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "Early in this opera, one character contemplates a lover in the aria \u201cAh, fors\u2019e lui\u201d before finding a camellia flower to give him. Another man sings \u201cDi provenza\u201d in this opera to console his son about a failed relationship, and Doctor Grenvil tells the maid Annina about the condition of a character who sings (*) \u201cSempre Libera\u201d at the end of this opera\u2019s first act. Baron Douphol is used to make another man jealous in this opera at a party where Alfredo sings \u201cLibiamo ne'lieti calici\u201d The title character dies of tuberculosis in, for 10 points, what Giuseppe Verdi opera about \u201cthe fallen\u201d Violetta?", "answer": "La Traviata (accept The Fallen Woman)", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This work contains a reference to J.K. Huysmans\u2019 \u201cAgainst Nature\u201d that the protagonist says \u201cpoisoned him.\u201d One character in this work is called \u201cPrince Charming\u201d by another character, an actress named Sybil Vane. The central object of this novel disappoints its creator because it shows too much (*) feeling for the subject. The subject of that object eventually kills the creator, Basil Hallward, after he sees the now hideous titular object. For ten points, name this novel about a cursed artwork that bears the burden of age and ruin while the subject stays young and beautiful, a novel by Oscar Wilde.", "answer": "The Picture of Dorian Gray", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The Chamizal Dispute saw conflict over the natural movement of this entity. The IBWC holds some jurisdiction over this area whose initial structure was established by the 1828 Treaty of Limits. The Battle of Columbus occurred after an illegal crossing of this boundary, which was the subject of the Secure (*) Fence Act of 2006. The Rio Grande makes up much of this border whose busiest checkpoint divides San Diego from Tijuana. For ten points, name this most frequently crossed geopolitical boundary in the world which separates North America\u2019s two most populous countries.", "answer": "US-Mexico Border (or obvious equivalents, prompt on answers mentioning only the U.S. or Mexico)", "category": "Geography", "subcategory": "Geography"}, {"question": "Mark Rothko\u2019s No. 6 features this color between violet and red. A pair of boots of this color appear in the top left of A Bar at the Folies-Berg\u00e8re and both Manet and Degas painted absinthe as a shade of this color. Unlike his (*) Yellow Christ, Gauguin's Christ of this color is no longer on the cross. The woman in The Arnolfini Wedding wears a dress of this color and Henri Matisse painted a portrait of his wife with a stripe of this color down the middle. For 10 points, name this secondary color made by mixing blue and yellow.", "answer": "green", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "According to Alfv\u00e9n\u2019s Theorem, for a perfectly conducting fluid the flux of this entity through a surface is conserved. In order to account for this entity into its associated Lagrangian, a vector potential must be introduced. In the presence of a static one of these, a spectral line splits; that is the (*) Zeeman Effect. The strength of this entity can be measured for steady currents using the Biot\u2013Savart law. According to Maxwell\u2019s equations, the divergence of this entity is 0. This vector field, when crossed with the product of velocity and charge, gives its associated force. For 10 points, name this field whose strength is measured in Teslas.", "answer": "magnetic field (accept B-field or H-field, prompt on \u201cB\u201d or \u201cH\u201d)", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "Henry Charles Carey encouraged the strengthening of these laws during the Civil War. Article 1, Section 9 of the Constitution bans one type of this law, and Alexander Hamilton supported one of these laws to cover Revolutionary War debts. In 1833, Andrew Jackson signed the \u201cForce Bill\u201d to enforce one of these laws in (*) South Carolina. Historical examples of these laws include those named for Oscar Underwood and William McKinley, and Herbert Hoover supported the Hawley-Smoot one of these laws to fight the Great Depression. For ten points, name these often-controversial taxes on international trade.", "answer": "tariff (accept import tariff, prompt on \u201ctax\u201d)", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "In a short story by this author, Callisto thinks about the increasing disorder of the American consumerist society, equating it to the title concept \u201cEntropy.\u201d Another short story by this author is about two English spies named Porpentine and Goodfellow. Both of these stories appear in this author\u2019s collection Slow Learner. In a novel by this author, a (*) muted post horn continually follows the protagonist, Oedipa Maas. Another novel by this author begins with \u201cA screaming comes across the sky\u201d and is possibly titled for the trajectory of a V-2 rocket. For ten points, name this author of The Crying of Lot 49 and Gravity\u2019s Rainbow.", "answer": "Thomas Pynchon Jr", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "A law describing these objects is called the S\u00e9rsic profile and has a special case called de Vaucouleurs' law. A mathematical model for predicting the number of these objects with mass between M and M+dM is named for Press and Schechter. The winding problem concerns these objects, which can be classified as flocculant or grand-design based on the definition of their structure by (*) Lin-Shu density wave theory. The Faber\u2013Jackson and Tully\u2013Fisher relations regard the luminosities of these objects. For 10 points, name these star systems classified on Hubble\u2019s tuning fork diagram as lenticular, elliptical or spiral.", "answer": "galaxies (or galaxy)", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "P.M. Markey studied this effect over the internet using the screen names Suzy and Jake Harmen. A television show hosted by John Qui\u00f1ones tests this effect which Darley and Latan\u00e9 studied by slowly filling a room with smoke. Social proof, pluralistic ignorance, and diffusion of (*) responsibility are reasons proposed to explain this phenomenon. Good Samaritan laws attempt to diminish this effect which is often exemplified by Winston Moseley\u2019s 1964 murder of Kitty Genovese. For ten points, name this phenomenon whereby individuals in a large group do not offer help in an emergency.", "answer": "bystander effect (accept bystander apathy) HALFTIME", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science"}, {"question": "The E minor overture \u201cSinfony\u201d opens this work. Part Two of this work starts in G minor before suddenly dropping an octave and later shifts to 3/4 time on the line \u201cThou art gone up on high.\u201d Charles Jennens wrote the libretto for this piece and King (*) George II supposedly rose from his seat during one performance of it. The most famous aspect of this work includes the line \u201che shall reign for ever and ever\u201d and is performed in D major with angelic trumpets and timpani. For ten points, name this oratorio by George Frederic Handel which includes the \u201cHallelujah\u201d chorus.", "answer": "Messiah", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "One character in a work by this author reacts angrily after mistaking a man for the monk Peter Damian. The family of that character changes his home into a palace at Goslar in order to humor him, because he believes himself to be a king after falling off of a horse. That play centers around the title people rehearsing (*) The Rules of the Game, another work by this author. It begins with The Director disbelieving The Father about his family\u2019s status. For ten points, name this playwright of Henry IV and Six Characters in Search of an Author.", "answer": "Luigi Pirandello", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "During embryogenesis, this organ develops from its ventral and dorsal buds. In this organ, epsilon cells produce the \u201chunger hormone\u201d, ghrelin, while acinar cells compose this organ\u2019s exocrine gland. This organ\u2019s Duct of Santorini isn\u2019t present in most people, and its Duct of Wirsung empties its contents into the (*) duodenum. This organ\u2019s endocrine cells are contained in its Islets of Langerhans. Trypsinogen, amylase, and lipase are found in its namesake juice. Somatostatin is produced by its delta cells, while its beta cells produce glucagon. For ten points, name this digestive organ that secretes insulin.", "answer": "pancreas", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "It\u2019s not the Cistercian order, but Saint Bernard of Clairvaux helped establish this organization\u2019s structure. The papal bull Omne Datum Optimum established this organization in 1139, while the recently discovered Chinon Parchment absolved its leadership of heresy. This organization triumphed at the Battle of Montgisard, while members of this organization captured at the Battle of (*) Hattin were executed by Saladin. The final grandmaster of this order was Hugh de Molay, who was burnt at the stake when Philip IV and Pope Clement V disbanded it. For ten points, name this Christian military order which protected pilgrims travelling to Jerusalem.", "answer": "Knights Templar (in full: Poor Fellow-Soldiers of Christ and of the Temple of Solomon, accept either underlined portion)", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "The Abhidharma-kosa is a text that describes a Buddhist example of this thing, Naraka. A goddess in Babylonian mythology was forced to remove her clothing in seven phases in order to gain access to one of these. The Aztec variety of this concept consists of nine levels and is called (*) Mictlan, and it is ruled over by Xolotl. The Norse version of this place is ruled over by a daughter of Loki, and the Greek version of it shares its name with the brother of Zeus and Poseidon who rules over it. For 10 points, name these realms of the dead, the Greek version of which is ruled over by Hades.", "answer": "underworlds (accept Hell before \u2018Mictlan\u2019, accept Hades before reading)", "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology"}, {"question": "One compound with this property, thiophene, includes an atom of sulfur, as does sulbentine, which possesses this property in three locations. Ladderanes are composed of molecules with this property. The placing of a double bond at the bridgehead of a molecule with this property is described by (*) Bredt\u2019s rule. Ethers with this property include lithium ionophore V and 18-crown-6, and hydrocarbons with this property are called annulenes. The Simmons\u2013Smith reaction yields propane with aromaticity and this property, which is possessed by molecules with half-chair and twist-boat conformations. For 10 points, name this property exhibited by benzene rings.", "answer": "cyclic (accept rings or anything with cyclo-, prompt on \u201caromatic\u201d)", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "As an infant, this man was saved by Harpagus, who later helped this man seize power from his grandfather Astyages. This leader commissioned the Chapar Khaneh postal service, and his Edict of Restoration earned him praise in the Book of Isaiah. This man defeated Nabonidus at the Battle of the Opis and bested Croesus at the Battle of Thymbra to conquer the (*) Lydian Empire. This author of a namesake \u201ccylinder\u201d was killed fighting the Massagetae queen Tomyris and founded Pasargadae as his imperial capital. For 10 points, name this founder of the Achaemenid Persian Empire.", "answer": "Cyrus II (accept Cyrus the Great)", "subcategory": "History Classical", "category": "History"}, {"question": "In this novel, a liquor seller living on Hyacinth Street is called a \u201cqueen.\u201d While in a courtroom, a character in this novel states that he fired at a tree with his revolver and claims that another character carried a \u201cblessed\u201d iron bar. A character in this novel fails to find Sibeko\u2019s daughter at (*) Barbara Smith\u2019s house, and another dies while writing a manuscript titled \u201cThe Truth about Native Crime.\u201d In this novel, Matthew and Johannes Parfuri help commit a murder, and Msimangu asks Stephen to come to Johannesburg. For 10 points, name this novel about the killing of Arthur Jarvis by Absalom Kumalo, written by Alan Paton.", "answer": "Cry, the Beloved Country", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "Anekantavada is a principle of this religion stating that reality has multiple aspects. Practitioners of this faith often fast during Paryushana, one of its most important festivals, and its primary symbol shows three dots, a swastika, and an open palm. The Tattvarthasutra is the most sacred of the (*) Agamas of this religion. The two primary divisions of the religion are the Svetambara and the Digambara, also known as white-clad and skyclad. For 10 points, name this Indian religion whose current Tirthankara is Mahavira and that emphasizes the principle of ahimsa, or nonviolence.", "answer": "Jainism (accept Jain Dharma)", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion"}, {"question": "In November 2017, this company began talks to create a television adaptation of Lord of the Rings. The CEO of this company asserts that \u201cyour margin is my opportunity\u201d while the city of Stonecrest, Georgia recently offered to rename itself for this corporation. In Fall 2017, this company launched a request for proposal to build a $5 billion (*) headquarters dubbed HQ2, receiving bids from over 200 different cities. This corporation also released the Key service in October 2017, a home security system connected with its Alexa assistant. For ten points, name this online retail giant founded by Jeff Bezos.", "answer": "Amazon.com, Inc.", "category": "Trash", "subcategory": "Trash"}, {"question": "This character says that a certain group of people\u2019s members are \u201cstill in their childhood.\u201d In another work, this character says that he doesn\u2019t know how to build a snowman. This character stays outside of a jail all night in order to protect another character. He also makes his children read to (*) Mrs. Dubose until she comes off a morphine addiction. This lawyer fights on behalf of Tom Robinson against Bob Ewell, pointing out that the prosecution has produced no medical evidence of the crime. For ten points, name this character who appears in Harper Lee\u2019s To Kill a Mockingbird, the father of Scout Finch.", "answer": "Atticus Finch (accept Atticus, prompt on \u201cFinch\u201d) Bonuses", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}], "bonuses": [{"leadin": "Robert de Boron described Joseph of Arimathea\u2019s acquisition of this object. For ten points each:", "answers": [": Holy Grail", "Sir Galahad", "Sir Percival"], "parts": ["Name this cup that Jesus used at the Last Supper which was sought after by King Arthur and the Knights of the Round Table.", "This knight of the Round Table was able to sit at the Siege Perilous as it was his destiny to find the Holy Grail.", "This knight pursued the Holy Grail before Galahad. This man meets the Fisher King before Galahad rescues him from a group of rival knights."], "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology"}, {"leadin": "The Oh-My-God particle is an ultra-high-energy type of this particle. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["cosmic rays", "cosmic microwave background radiation (accept CMBR)", "protons (accept hydrogen nuclei, hydrogen ions, or H+)"], "parts": ["Name this particle whose theoretical energy is cut off at the GZK limit.", "The interaction of cosmic rays with this leftover blackbody radiation sets the GZK limit. It is evidence of the Big Bang and causes the universe to have a temperature of 2.7 Kelvin.", "Of the nuclei in cosmic rays, 1% are HZE ions, 9% are alpha particles, and 90% are these particles."], "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "Answer the following questions about American hip hop group NWA. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Straight Outta Compton", "Eazy-E (accept Eric Lynn Wright, prompt on \u201cEazy\u201d or \u201cE\u201d)", "Jerry Heller"], "parts": ["NWA rose to fame with this 1988 album. Its namesake track references the group\u2019s origins in a certain city in south Los Angeles.", "NWA was led by Dr. Dre, Ice Cube, and this rapper and founder of Ruthless Records. This man died in March 1995 from complications of AIDS.", "This controversial manager of NWA is often cited as a reason for the group\u2019s breakup. Paul Giamatti played this man in the 2015 film Straight Outta Compton."], "category": "Trash", "subcategory": "Trash"}, {"leadin": "Bill Clinton\u2019s administration was often rocked by scandal. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Monica Lewinsky", "Whitewater Affair (accept equivalents mentioning \u201cWhitewater\u201d)", "Vince Foster"], "parts": ["Clinton was impeached in 1998 for lying about his affair with this White House intern. After the affair became public, this woman and her blue dress became internationally known.", "Much of the evidence concerning Clinton\u2019s relationship with Lewinsky was uncovered through the investigation of this other Clinton controversy. This scandal involved a failed real estate investment made with Jim and Susan McDougal.", "Beyond the Lewinsky and Whitewater Scandals, Clinton was less rationally accused of orchestrating the death of this Deputy White House Counsel and boyhood friend of Clinton\u2019s who took his own life in 1993."], "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "In Chapter 18 of the Book of Matthew, Jesus preaches to his disciples about forgiveness. For ten points each:", "answers": ["St. Peter (accept Simon Peter, prompt on \u201cSimon\u201d)", "seventy times seven (accept 490)", "servant (or equivalents)"], "parts": ["Christ\u2019s lecture on forgiveness is prompted by a question from this disciple. This first pope was forgiven by Jesus for denying him three times.", "Peter asked Christ how many times to forgive someone who wronged him, suggesting seven as a reasonable answer. Jesus instead says to forgive someone this many times. Expression answer acceptable.", "Christ stresses the importance of forgiveness with a parable about one of these people. In the story, a man with this profession is forgiven of a debt but still attempts to collect money someone else owes him."], "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion"}, {"leadin": "One prominent artist of this movement, Andy Warhol, operated a studio known as \"The Factory\". For ten points each,", "answers": ["Pop Art", "Campbell's Soup Cans", "Jasper Johns"], "parts": ["Name this 1950s art movement that highlighted common objects and mass-culture.", "Warhol produced 32 canvases showing varieties of this packaged food product, which are now housed in the Museum of Modern Art.", "Another prominent pop artist was this man who used newsprint collages and shades of white to create numerous depictions of the American flag."], "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "This man used the pseudonyms Victor Eremita, A, B, and Johannes in his book <em>Either/Or.</em> For ten points each:", "answers": ["S\u00f8ren Kierkegaard", "knight of faith (prompt on \u201cknight\u201d)", "existentialism"], "parts": ["Name this Danish philosopher who wrote Fear and Trembling.", "In Fear and Trembling, Kierkegaard uses this term to denote individuals whose belief in God frees them from earthly tethers. Kierkegaard offers the Virgin Mary and Abraham as two examples of this concept.", "Kierkegaard founded and embodied this school of philosophy which embraces the need for human free agency in philosophical thinking. Simone de Beauvoir and Albert Camus also embraces this philosophy."], "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy"}, {"leadin": "These entities are added head to tail using the parallelogram rule. For ten points each:", "answers": ["vectors", "cross product [or crossing]", "seven"], "parts": ["Name these objects that have magnitude and direction.", "The direction of the result of this operation on two vectors can be found using the right hand rule. This operation is defined as the product of the magnitudes of two vectors multiplied by the sine of the angle between them.", "The cross product in this dimension does not satisfy the Jacobi identity. Cross products only exists in three dimensions and in spaces with this number of dimensions."], "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This region fell under Communist control after the Battle of Chamdo. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Tibet", "14th Dalai Lama (accept Tenzin Gyatso)", "Lhasa"], "parts": ["Name this mountainous region of Southwestern China which staged a violent uprising against socialist reform in 1959. An international movement seeks to \u201cfree\u201d this region.", "The Tibetan government-in-exile is headed by this man, who also leads the Gelug school of Tibetan Buddhism. This man won the Nobel Peace Prize in 1989.", "Before the Dalai Lama was driven out of Tibet, he governed from the Potala Palace in this city, the historical and current capital of Tibet."], "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "Music and literature often go hand in hand. For ten points each, name these literary titles that contain musically inclined characters.", "answers": ["Pride and Prejudice", "The Awakening", "The Kreutzer Sonata"], "parts": ["In this Jane Austen novel, Georgiana Darcy is considered by Caroline Bingley to be an \u201caccomplished woman\u201d because of her prowess as a singer and with the piano and harp.", "In this novel, Mademoiselle Reisz teaches the protagonist how to play the piano. The protagonist admires Mademoiselle Reisz in the novel because she will not conform to the New Orleans Creole society.", "This Tolstoy novella relates the story of a man who killed his wife after he learned of her affair with a violinist."], "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "This park contains the largest public herd of bison in the United States. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Yellowstone National Park", "Snake River", "Hells Canyon"], "parts": ["Name this national park in Wyoming, Montana, and Idaho which includes Old Faithful geyser and a massive caldera.", "This river of the Pacific Northwest has its source in Yellowstone. This river flows into the Columbia in Walla Walla, Washington", "The Snake River carved out this canyon, the deepest in North America, about six million years ago."], "category": "Geography", "subcategory": "Geography"}, {"leadin": "This government unsuccessfully attempt to preserve colonies in Mozambique, Angola, and Guinea Bissau. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Estado Novo", "Portugal", "Carnation Revolution"], "parts": ["Name this authoritarian regime dominated by Ant\u00f3nio Salazar. It shares its name with Get\u00falio Vargas\u2019 similarly authoritarian Brazilian government.", "The Estado Novo governed this European country with capital at Lisbon.", "In 1974, the Estado Novo was finally overthrown in this liberal military coup. This revolution gets its name from the flowers protesters placed in rifle barrels."], "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "For ten points each, name some composers who were dubbed part of \u201cThe Mighty Five\u201d or \u201cThe Mighty Handful\u201d by Vladimir Stasov.", "answers": ["Alexander Borodin", "Mily Balakirev", "Russia (anti-prompt on \u201cSoviet Union\u201d or \u201cUSSR\u201d)"], "parts": ["This member of \u201cThe Mighty Five\u201d wrote Prince Igor, and In the Steppes of Central Asia.", "This other member of \u201cThe Mighty Five\u201d wrote folk tunes such as Islamey and Tamara, but he is better known for being a teacher of Borodin and Mussorgsky.", "\u201cThe Mighty Five\u201d hailed from this country. Other composers from this country include Tchaikovsky and Rachmaninoff."], "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "One character in this story is nicknamed \u201cQueenie\u201d by its narrator because of her attractiveness. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["A&amp;P", "\u201cA Supermarket in California\u201d", "Japan"], "parts": ["Name this John Updike short story told from the perspective of the grocery store clerk Sammy who quits his job to impress some girls.", "In this poem, Allen Ginsberg writes about seeing Garcia Lorca \u201cdown by the watermelons\u201d at the title place.", "A group of kids rebel against a Korean supermarket owner in The Silent Cry by Kenzaburo Oe, an author from this East Asian country and birthplace of 2017 Nobel Prize winner Kazuo Ishiguro."], "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "This technique uses a burette to dispense a reagent. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["titration", "phenolphthalein (prompt on \"HIn\" or \"phph,\u201d prompt on \u201cC20H14O4\u201d)", "glycine"], "parts": ["Name this lab technique that determines the concentration of the analyte and uses indicators that change color.", "In an acid-base titration, this compound may be used as the indicator. When the pH of the solution is between 8.3 and 10, this indicator\u2019s color changes from colorless to pink.", "The titration curve of this amino acid has two equivalence points because it is a diprotic acid. The side chain of this simplest amino acid is a hydrogen atom."], "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This movement was effectively crushed by an 1813 mass trial in York. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Luddite Movement", "textiles (accept weaving or equivalents)", "stocking frames (accept mechanical looms, prompt on \u201clooms\u201d)"], "parts": ["Name this popular movement in nineteenth century England which fought industrialization. Today, the name of this movement is applied to those who fight technological progress.", "The Luddites primarily opposed the mechanization of this industry, long a key part of the British economy because of the isles\u2019 plentiful wool. Manchester was a major hub of this industry.", "A common form of Luddite protest was the destruction of these items. An 1812 law made breaking one of these machines a capital offence."], "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "Many literary characters and their authors have taken an interest in painting. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Jane Eyre (accept either underlined name)", "William Blake", "Cat\u2019s Eye"], "parts": ["This character\u2019s paintings of a shipwreck and a cormorant, the evening star, and a head seem to foreshadow her story at Thornfield Hall.", "This poet was a well known artist who painted works like The Ancient of Days and illustrations for his poems, including The Lamb and The Tyger.", "This novel by Margaret Atwood follows a modern painter named Elaine Risley reflecting on her childhood and teenage years."], "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "Diane Arbus's \"Child with a Hand Grenade\" was created in this medium. For ten points each:", "answers": ["photography", "group f/64 (pronounced F stop 64.", "The de Young Museum"], "parts": ["Name this medium also used by Dorothea Lange in her \"Migrant Mother\" and other depictions of the Great Depression.", "Many photographs of western life during the Great Depression were captured by members of this artistic group founded by artists like Ansel Adams and Imogen Cunningham. This group is named after the smallest aperture on a large-format camera.", "The first f/64 exhibition was held at this San Francisco art museum. This museum\u2019s copper clad building and distinctive Hamon Tower were designed by Herzog &amp; de Meuron."], "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "Muscle paralysis can occur in the REM phase of this behavior. For ten points each:", "answers": ["sleep", "melatonin (accept N-acetyl-5-methoxy tryptamine)", "follicle-stimulating hormone (accept FSH)"], "parts": ["Name this state restricted by insomnia.", "The onset of sleep is signaled by the secretion of this hormone, used to treat insomnia and produced by the pineal gland.", "Melatonin can lower the levels of this reproductive hormone, which is produced with luteinizing hormone in the anterior pituitary gland."], "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "Literature and herpetology, or the study of amphibians, are not mutually exclusive! For ten points each:", "answers": ["\u201cThe Tortoise and the Hare\u201d", "The Frogs", "The Night of the Iguana"], "parts": ["This Aesop fable features a race between two animals culminating in a moral that \u201cslow and steady\u201d is better than fast and lazy.", "This play about Dionysus and his slave Xanthius attempting to bring Euripides from the dead includes the title amphibians chanting \u201cBrekekek\u00e8x-ko\u00e0x-ko\u00e1x.\u201d", "This Tennessee William plays examines Reverend T. Lawrence Shannon after he is accused of statutory rape."], "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "This event was planned and supported by a coalition of oligarchs from the Satsuma and Ch\u014dsh\u016b Provinces. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Meiji Restoration (or equivalents mentioning Meiji)", "Boshin War (prompt on \u201cJapanese Revolution\u201d)", "Matthew Perry"], "parts": ["Name this event in 19th century Japan in which the Tokugawa Shogunate collapsed and a modernizing teenage emperor gained true imperial authority.", "The Meiji Restoration was immediately preceded by this military conflict, in which pro-imperial forces decisively defeated allies of the Shogunate.", "The Tokugawa Shogunate\u2019s terminal decline began when this American commodore forcibly opened Japan to foreign trade. This man\u2019s older brother Oliver led the U.S. to victory in the Battle of Lake Erie."], "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}]}